Good afternoon.
>> Good evening everybody. It's high noon
in Old Cheyenne. Welcome to the June 2nd
Finance Committee meeting. I call that
meeting to order.
Ask everybody in the
public here to make sure your phones are
on vibrate or mute. When making public
comment, clearly identify yourself.
Use the raise hand function online and
our staff will let you know you can
unmute yourself.
Uh
after the completion of this agenda, no
additional business will
be discussed. All uh communications go
through the chair.
And with that, clerk, read the first
item.
>> Number nine, ordinance third reading
amending and updating the solid waste
fee schedule in accordance with section
8.44.010
of the municipal code of the city of
Cheyenne, Wyoming and repealing
ordinance number 4621.
>> Staff report.
>> Good afternoon, Craig LeVoy, Public
Works.
Um
The WDQ requires municipalities to
update our integrated solid waste master
plan every 10 years, and we did a full
cost analysis with this in 2019, and
these are the rates that they proposed
for the next 10 years.
And the increases will be for
residential trash and recycling 1%.
Commercial trash will be 3%. Commercial
recycling will be at 5%. Disposable at
our transfer station is 2%, and
roll-offs
are 3%, and your yard waste services
will increase by 1%, and I
recommend approval. Thank you.
>> Any questions from anyone on the
committee for staff?
Seeing none, we'll go to public comment
in the room.
No public comment in the room. Public
comment online?
No public comment online. Close public
comment. Come back to the committee. Any
final questions or comments?
Okay. Okay. What's your pleasure?
>> Mr. Chair, I move to approve on third
and final reading.
>> Moved by Councilman Wright, seconded by
Councilman Wolf. Any further comments?
All those in favor signify by saying
aye.
Any opposed?
>> No.
>> That motion is uh
to
the governing body will be to approve
the next meeting with Councilman Moody
voting no. Next item.
>> Number 13, ordinance third reading
approving and establishing revised water
and sewer rates, tap and system
development fees, administrative fees,
service charges and penalties, and
septic and commercial waste dump rates
as recommended by the Board of Public
Utilities.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chairman and committee, Brad Bowan,
admin manager for Cheyenne Board of
Public Utilities.
In front of you is the annual rate
ordinance for rates to be effective
October 1.
A quick summary of the rates would be a
3% in the monthly service fee, a 5% in
tier one and tier two rates on the
residential side. Commercial side is
going to be based pretty much by a
percentage of overall usage.
System development fees at 5%,
administrative fees were modified based
off of covering costs, and septic and
commercial dump rates increased by 5%,
and I stand for any questions.
>> Questions or comments from the committee
for staff?
Let's see, and then we'll go to public
comment in the room.
Any public comment online?
Back to the committee, can I get a
motion?
>> Uh Mr. Chairman, um
I move to approve on third and final
reading.
>> Second.
>> Moved by Councilman Wolf, seconded by
Councilman White. Any further
discussion?
All in favor, signify by saying I.
Any opposed?
>> No.
>> The recommendation of the finance
committee at the next meeting of the
governing body will be to approve with
Councilman Moody voting no. Next item.
>> Number 15, ordinance second reading,
defining the terms and conditions for
employment of employment for sworn
officers of the Cheyenne Police
Department for July 2026 until the end
of fiscal year 2027.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chairman members of the committee,
Captain David James, Cheyenne Police
Department. What you have before you is
the annual terms and conditions for
sworn employees. Uh this follows the uh
budget requests uh that you that you're
currently working on. The biggest
changes in for the next year are the 3%
salary adjustment, uh on-call specialty
pay, we've raised them all into one
single level, where before we had two
different levels, and the uh
incorporation of a corporal rank uh
within the
uh terms and conditions and I stand for
any questions.
>> Questions for the committee for Captain
James?
Seeing none, go to public comment in the
room.
Public comment online?
Nothing. Back to the committee. What's
your pleasure?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to approve on
second reading.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Moody,
seconded by Councilman Wolf. Any other
further discussion?
Ready to
Any Everybody in favor signify by saying
I.
Seeing that vote is unanimous, the
recommendation of the Finance Committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to approve. Next item.
>> Number 25, resolution authorizing the
city of Cheyenne
Utilities to discharge uncollectible
debts pursuant to Wyoming State Statute
16-4-502.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chairman and Committee, Brad Bowen,
Admin Manager, Cheyenne Board of Public
Utilities. In front of you is a
resolution for BOPU to write off
$18,317.24.
This is after BOPU's finished its
collection process.
The writing off does not halt the
collection process. It just allows us to
stay within GAAP financials of being
able to have
the debt written off the books, but the
collection agency will still continue
collections.
And I stand for any questions.
>> Councilman White.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chair. Through you to
either Brad or or Robin. I know my
colleague
Dr. Aldridge has always been very
interested in this item and and I've
been interested, too. Um
Robin, correct me if I'm wrong, but
$18,000 sounds
pretty
pretty good compared to
past years as far as
um
collections. Am I wrong on that?
Or I'll let you answer. Sorry. Sorry,
Robin.
>> Mr. Chairman, to Councilman White, it is
roughly right in there. There was a
couple years ago that we had a very
large write-off and that was when BOPU
switched from carrying the debt for 7
years to move in line with the city
where we only keep 4 years worth of
debt. As a percentage, I don't have it
in my paperwork with me, but we are
still far below the national average uh
compared to other water utilities on our
collection rates.
>> Thank you. And and you know, in looking
through some of these, I know I you
know, I see bankruptcies and and um
unfortunately some passings and and I
know there's nothing that can be done
about things like that, but just know
that we appreciate your efforts to uh
to try and
uh collect some of these
fees who have uh or folks who may have
just left and move moved away from town
and didn't
thought not to pay what they owed, so
appreciate your efforts. Thank you.
Thank you, Mr. Chair.
>> Thank you. Uh
Anything else from the committee before
we go to public comment?
Okay.
Public comment in the room?
Any public comment online?
And bring it back to the committee.
It's your pleasure.
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to adopt.
>> Second.
>> Been moved by Councilman Wolsic and by
Councilman White. Any further
discussions?
All in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Seeing that that vote is unanimous, the
recommendation of the Finance Committee
to the next meeting of the governing
body will be to adopt. Next item.
>> Number 27, resolution authorizing the
acceptance of a donation for affordable
housing purposes and authorizing the
mayor to execute a donation agreement.
>> Staff
Mr. Mayor.
>> Mr. Chairman, members of the committee,
for the record, I'm Mayor Patrick
Collins.
Today is, I think, the culmination of a
lot of work that started at a dinner I
attended in October of 2025.
I was sharing with uh Related CEO, Jeff
Blau, about our housing challenges and
other things that we're facing as a
community.
Uh their company's core business is
housing, and so they understood.
And I talked about how we were trying to
recruit an affordable housing developer
using 4% low-income housing tax credits,
something that's never been done in
Wyoming.
The next day at the groundbreaking,
Related Digital uh of their $1.2 billion
investment in our community, Mr. Blau
surprised all of us with announcement
that they would uh be giving a $3.5
million donation
to complete the funding necessary for
the affordable housing project that
we've been working on for more than 3
years.
Today is a culmination of all that work.
We have an affordable housing developer
ready to begin building 184 housing
units.
The next step is to accept this gift,
and that's what we're going to do today,
and get the building process started. Um
I want to thank Steamboat Property
Owners LLC um for their understanding of
the need for affordable housing in our
city, and for their investment of $3.5
million to help make a 184 million or
184 unit affordable housing project
happen.
They are really my heroes, you guys. Um
our our affordable housing effort would
be at a standstill
uh but for their amazing gift and their
commitment to housing in Cheyenne. And
I'll stand for any questions.
>> Questions or comments from the committee
for the mayor?
>> Is the group
Okay, we'll go out to public comment in
the room.
Any public comment in the room on this
item?
Public comment online.
Seeing none, I'll come back to the
committee, close public comment.
Committee, what's your pleasure?
>> Mr. Chair, I move to adopt.
>> Been moved by Councilman White, seconded
by Councilman Wolf. Any further
discussion?
All in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Any opposed?
>> No.
>> Recommendation of the Finance Committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to
adopt with Councilman Moody voting no.
Next item.
>> Number 28B, real estate purchase
agreement between the City of Cheyenne
and KT Land Holdings LLC for 8.37 acres
of land located at Lot 1, Block 1,
Scenic Development 8th Filing, a portion
of Section 20, Township 14 North, Range
66 West of the 6th PM, Laramie County,
Wyoming.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chairman,
members of the Finance Committee, for
the record, I'm Mayor Patrick Collins.
In our last uh resolution, we accepted a
gift from Related Digital via Steamboat
Property LLC for $3.5 million.
And the next step is to put that gift to
work building the much-needed affordable
housing. Before you and for your
consideration, we have a real estate
purchase agreement between the city and
KT Land Holdings LLC.
It's 8.37 acres. We had it appraised,
the city did, came in at $2,645,000.
Um the city is going to obtain a title
commitment, for which the city will pay
for, and the agreement also lists all
the other opportunities that had the
city has to make sure the uh property
purchase is right for the city.
The seller will disclose all of the
documents referred to in the title
commitment. Uh all documents known to
the seller, soils, geological,
engineering studies, um,
all the copies of environmentals, any
notice of violations, all mortgages,
notes, and liens, um, that encumber the
property.
Um, copies of any litigation, all the
things that you would expect in a
property transaction. The plan is once
the property is acquired by the city,
then we'll enter into a long-term lease
with the, uh, builder. Um, that should
come before you here soon. Um, and, uh,
then we'll get those
affordable housing built. It's actually
going to be built literally kitty-corner
to where the large fire was the other
day, so, um, kind of a heartbreaker for
us. Um,
but it's the it's, uh, the same company
that was doing that that large
construction. They have an affordable
housing, uh, division, and that's where
the housing will be built.
I'll stand for any questions, sir.
>> Councilman
White.
>> Uh, Mr. Chair, through you, Mr. Mayor,
due to the recent unfortunate
fire event that occurred out there, is
that going to, um, hold up the the
progress of this particular development
while they, I mean, cuz I believe that's
still under investigation and
what the what the developer does with
that
after suffering such a loss is going to
be up to them, but
>> Yeah, Mr. Chairman.
>> will this development up?
>> Mr. Chairman, through you to Mr. White,
um, I did meet a couple of times now in
the last week with the, uh,
the developer of the apartment that was
burned and, uh,
like they said, really they have
insurance. They were two and a half
months ahead of schedule because of our
nice winter, and they had 72 apartment
building, uh, unit apartment building.
It was literally they'd finished, uh,
all the, uh, sheeting and framing on the
outside, and they were they literally
loaded it up with drywall to start that
process. Um, they were they were really
cooking. Um, but, uh, they're committed
to, uh,
building the housing that we need. When
we first met with them, I challenged
them that we needed a thousand units by
2030. And now they're talking about
building 2,000 units and you know, so
I'm very appreciative of them.
To my knowledge sir, this should not
stop this project moving forward. The
ATF is there right now doing their
investigation. As soon as they complete
that their their plan is to remediate
the site and start that burnout project
over and this project is not on that
site. It's across the street so we
should be able to move forward.
>> Councilman Wolf.
>> Mr. Chairman, thank you very much
through you. Mr. Mayor, I just want to
thank you for your work on both the
donation and on on this
acquisition and thank you chief of staff
and and uh
ready for I know a lot of work goes into
these kinds of projects and particularly
negotiating a an acquisition agreement.
So
thank you for all of that effort.
>> Mr. Chairman, through you, you know, I'm
not very often am I uh
out of words.
Um
but during that ground breaking when
they made that announcement, I was very
had a hard time finding words to say. It
was such a shock and
very appreciative of the fact that
companies um
you know, who come and invest in
Cheyenne um want to be part of helping
solve the solution and
the folks from Related again like I told
you they're uh
their main business is housing. That's
what they what they've done for the last
I don't know, 30 years and they really
truly understood the challenge and
wanted to be part of the solution. So
it was an awesome day. And when we cut
that ribbon, it's going to be a really
awesome day.
>> Okay.
Seeing there's no more further questions
from the committee, we'll go to public
comment in the room on this.
Public comment online.
Seeing none, we'll close public come
back to the committee. What's your
pleasure?
>> Uh Mr. Chairman, I move to approve.
>> Second.
>> Been moved by Councilman Wolf, second by
Councilman White. Any further
discussion?
All in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Any opposed?
>> No.
>> Recommendation of the Finance Committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to
approve with Councilman Moody voting no.
Next item.
>> Number 28C, Professional Services
Agreement between the City of Cheyenne
and AVI Professional Corporation for the
Parsley Boulevard and Willick Willick
Road Extension Feasibility Study.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chair
and committee, thank you. Uh this is
Christopher Yanni with the Cheyenne MPO
and uh here to
to uh request the uh proposal of
uh we did an advertisement for the uh on
the Cheyenne uh website and on the
Wyoming Tribune Eagle two times on
February 25th and 28th.
We received four proposals and uh the
following uh proposals were evaluated by
a committee and uh determined that AVI
Professional Corporation was selected as
the best um consultant for the um
project.
The proposal
is to look at two roads, Parsley
Boulevard and Willick Road Extension,
and see the feasibility of where this
alignment needs to occur in this area
between with Parsley between College
Drive down to Terry Ranch Road and
Willick Road from Division
um heading west over the railroad tracks
connecting up to
um College Drive.
Um the with the amount of growth and um
building um proposed in this area, We
need to establish these roads so that we
can, uh, define the roadway network in
this area.
>> Any questions or comments from the
committee for staff?
None?
Go to public comment in the room.
Seeing none, we'll go to public comment
online.
Okay, we'll close public comment. We'll
come back to the committee. What's your
pleasure?
>> Uh,
Mr. Chair, I move to approve in an
amount not to exceed $252,522.97.
>> Second.
Was that Moody?
It's been moved by Councilman Light,
seconded by Councilman Moody. Any
further comments or questions?
All in favor, signify by saying aye.
I see that that vote is unanimous. The
recommendation of the Finance Committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to approve. Next item.
>> Number 29A, renewal of contract 7535
between the City of Cheyenne and Blue
Cross Blue Shield of Wyoming for
third-party administrator services and
group health insurance benefits for city
employees.
>> Staff report.
>> Good afternoon, Mr. Chair, Finance
Committee.
Darren Hass, Human Resources and chair
of the commit employee benefit advisory
team.
Recommending another renewal, one-year
contract for Blue Cross Blue Shield to
serve as our third-party administrator
for the city's self-funded health care
plan.
The The contract renewal reflects a
slight increase on fixed administrative
fees.
Uh, we all know health care continues to
rise and it's going from $61.75,
$61.75
per member to $63.60.
Uh
we've enjoyed a 7-year partnership with
Blue Cross of Wyoming and truly
appreciate their healthcare platform.
Nobu Benefits has shopped many TPA
providers, vendors,
and again it's a challenge to find real
healthcare in Wyoming. So we are we're
always value where where we land for
uh affordable healthcare for employees.
And uh Nobu Benefits is also here with
me today. So I will stand for any
questions.
>> Any questions from the committee for
staff?
>> Just Mr. Chair, um
just
I'm continued to be very impressed with
the efforts from Nobu Benefits and
they've really uh
been able to uh
to find the best uh plans and rates that
that have
only
um caused slight increases over the last
several years. So um thank thank you to
them.
>> Remember Mr. Director,
uh
but always increases, when will it start
to decrease?
>> Uh I'm not sure we'll see it through in
my lifetime, sir.
>> Probably not in mine, either.
You get promises.
>> Okay.
>> Uh
go to public comment in the room.
>> No.
>> Seeing none, public comment online.
No public comment online. Close public
comment, come back to the committee.
What's your pleasure?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to
>> Go go ahead.
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to approve.
>> Second.
>> Been moved by Councilman Moody, second
by Councilman Lefein White. Any other
discussion?
All in favor signify family say "I".
>> I.
>> Seeing that that vote is unanimous, the
recommendation of the Finance Committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to approve. Next item.
>> Number 29B, renewal of contract 8183
between the City of Cheyenne and
Companion Life for stop-loss insurance
for city employees.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chair, Finance Committee, Darren
Hass, Human Resources.
This is a follow-up to our Blue Cross.
With any with any good plan or product,
you need insurance.
So, then we're recommending to renew a
contract with Companion to serve as our
stop-loss carrier
for the city's self-funded health care
plan.
The contract with Companion reflects a
9.2% increase in stop-loss fees and a
20.6 increase in overall claim costs.
In addition, the contract with Companion
does include Companion Care Gene Therapy
Program. We're excited about that.
Uh again, Novel Benefits has shopped
many stop-loss providers, vendors,
and in the end recommends Companion. So,
I stand for any questions.
>> Councilman White.
>> Sorry.
>> Councilman Wolf.
>> Uh thank you, Mr. Chairman. Through you,
um
Mr. Hass, are how many are there many
companies who are in this business of
offering the stop-loss covered?
>> Through you, Mr. Chair. There are quite
a few that do uh that do offer their
estimates and like to bid on these the
covered insurance, yes.
>> That's good to know. Thank you. Thank
you, Mr. Chairman.
>> Okay, we'll go to public comment in the
room.
Seeing none, public comment online.
Seeing none, we'll close the public
comment. Come back to the committee.
What's your pleasure?
>> Mr. Chair, I move to approve.
>> Second.
>> Moved by Councilman White, second by
Councilman Wolf. Any further
discussions?
All in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Seeing that that vote is unanimous, the
recommendation of the Finance Committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to approve next item.
>> Number 29C, renewal of contract 6837
between the City of Cheyenne and Delta
Dental for group dental insurance
benefits for the city for city
employees.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chair and Finance Committee, Darren
Hass from Human Resources.
And then the chair of the Employee
Benefit Advisory Team, we're
recommending renewal to the one-year
contract for our group dental plan
through Delta Dental.
Uh the exciting part of this is a rate
pass. No increase this year. Woohoo. So
and end on a good note, but I know I
stand for any questions. We we've had a
great partnership with Delta Dental and
we we'd love to keep them going.
>> Okay. Any questions or comments from
committee for staff?
But then we'll go to public comment in
the room.
Any public comment online on this item?
Seeing none, we'll close public comment
and come back to the committee. What's
your pleasure?
>> Uh Mr. Chairman, I move to approve.
>> Second.
>> Moved by Councilman Wolf, second by
Councilman Moody.
Any further discussion?
All in favor signify by saying I.
Seeing that that vote is unanimous, the
recommendation of the Finance Committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to approve next item.
>> Number 29D, contract modification number
two to contract number 8199 between the
City of Cheyenne and HDR Engineering
Incorporated for the 18th Street
Reconstruction Project.
>> Staff report.
>> Good afternoon, Chairman Esquerdo and
members of the Finance Committee, Tom
Cobb, City Engineer. Before you and for
your consideration is contract
modification number two to the City of
Cheyenne and HDR Engineering Inc.
Um, during the design phase of 18th
Street, and actually this was during our
pump house evaluation, we discovered uh
an a revised hydraulic assessment of
Crow Creek where we found that where we
were going to discharge 18th Street
would have caused a bigger issue than
what we had thought. It would make it
worse for everybody downstream. So, in
that we rerouted the storm sewer, and I
some of you have heard me say this, but
we went down Bent Avenue and the 15th
Street, and then we're taking it into
the wetland area there. So, eventually
I'm looking at trying to obtain UP
property to the south of our current
wetland to create a detention pond that
then will discharge into Crow Creek,
which then will go into what I call the
Clear Creek inline detention pond. We're
going to siphon off some of Crow Creek.
Complicated answer, three-component
project, but eventually this is a better
way of doing it where we discharge 18th
Street.
Um, as part of the scope change, we're
also then going to do a FEMA benefit
cost analysis um so that if we are
looking at trying to acquire future
federal funding, um that's part of that
requirement to do so, and that's been
added by this change order. We've got
obviously extended survey, some
additional geotech, um roadway drainage
and utility design revisions, um and
then we have to update our hydraulic and
hydrology modeling, and as I said, the
benefit cost analysis. The schedule
adjustment because of this change, we
are going to extend the contract to
December 31st of 2026. It will not
affect our FEMA funding because we will
be done with our our that part of the
project before that time.
Um, the funding for this is going to be
shared. Um, it's the 1% or fifth penny
optional tax. It will be split between
drainage and street improvements, and
it's for the amount of $313,197.
Um, obviously the redesign is necessary
to ensure the stormwater system
functions as intended within our capital
basin and to mitigate flooding risk and
to align with our long-term drainage
planning. The added work is essential
for completing the technical sound and
permit ready design for strengthening
our city storm sewer system. My
recommendation is to approve the
contract modification number two with
HDR in the amount of $313,197.
Mr. Todd Manson is here from HDR. If you
have any additional questions for him or
myself. Thank you.
>> Any comments or questions from the
committee for our city engineer?
Councilman White.
>> Mr. Chair, through you. Mr. Cobb, um
thank you for that information. Um just
know that I'm certainly in favor of this
project and know uh that it's going to
improve the the drainage aspect, but I'm
also very interested and support the uh
the street improvements that'll take
place
uh with this as well. But in the
description of changes,
you talk about um
uh will be designed to connect to the
existing overflow structure located
immediately north of Union Pacific
property. Um so and then you also
mentioned that um
you wanted to purchase a piece of
property. Well, we all know how that
goes sometimes
and um how long that might take. So, my
question is in the event that we're not
able to get that property
in our lifetime, um
just hope hoping hoping. Um
is is the project still going to to meet
the uh goals and um expectations that
you have?
>> Chairman Escobedo, through you to
Councilman White.
>> The answer is yes, sir. So, I have a
contingency plan. I've been working on
this purchase for 2 years. So, what will
happen in the event that we don't get
the property, as I said, I've got
another project in line, which is the
Clear Creek Inline Detention Facility.
That has two components to it. It'll
take offline some of Clear Creek and
take some of that water to the south. It
also then siphons off Crow Creek, and
what I've got planned to do is to take a
pipe and put it under the existing
channel underneath the Ames underpass,
which will siphon some of the water off
to take it to the south. Now, it's a
careful balance. We've been working on
that project for the last year, and it's
about to be due to get complete in
August, and I'd love to present that to
you. So, that's the contingency. Um and
again, what happens if it does overflow
in that area? It's simply, as we've
talked about before, the pump house area
is going to flood, and as I can't get it
out yet, when if I get another detention
pond in, it'll just assist us with
trying to mitigate some of that risk.
But, it'll work without it, if that
answers your question, sir.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chair.
>> Councilman Wolf.
>> Um thank you, Mr. Chair, through you. Um
uh Mr. Cobb, thank you, uh Director. Um
I just want to thank you for holding
that public hearing on the 18th Street
project. Um
uh fascinating set of maps and and uh
great opportunity to talk with the
people who are interested and are going
to be impacted by that. I mean, this is
this is a this is a major undertaking,
and that really congratulate you and
your staff for um keep keeping it moving
forward. So, thank you and thank them.
Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
>> Okay, we'll go to public comment in the
room.
Any public comment in the room on this
item?
Public comment online.
You guys sure that thing's working?
I don't know. Hopefully.
Awfully quiet out there.
All right. We'll come back the
committee. What's your pleasure?
>> Mr. Chair, I move to approve an amount
not to exceed $313,197.
>> Second.
>> Been moved by Councilman White, second
by Councilman Wolfe. Any further
discussion?
All in favor signify by saying aye.
>> Aye.
>> Seeing that that vote is unanimous, the
recommendation of the Finance Committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to approve.
Next item.
>> Number 30G, consideration of bid number
E-23-26
for furnishing one 58K JGBWR
lube truck, 2026 or newer for the fleet
division.
>> Okay, staff report.
>> Vicki Nemecek, Public Works. This is a
new lube truck for our fleet maintenance
division. It uh has a couple of exciting
upgrades. Um one is is that we have it
has a full-width heated and lighted van
body mounted on the truck, which means
that all the fluids that we carry around
will be inside that heated area, so it
will um be more efficient. It will pump
easier. It will be easier on the
equipment. So, that's one exciting
thing, and that also will um we're
increasing the size of the unleaded tank
by 200 gallons. So, we'll have a
600-gallon diesel and a 400-gallon
uh
unleaded fuel tank on this truck.
The uh
lowest responsive bid was Floyd's Truck
Center.
It The um
bid did include uh contingency, so for
the original equipment manufacturer and
or body surcharges
that might be applied to the cost of the
vehicle after the bid opening date, and
any model year escalators are covered in
this contingency.
So, the truck itself cost was $424,346.
Then you subtract the $15,000 for the
2009 well-used and well-loved old truck,
and you get the uh
and then add the contingency of
$63,651.90,
and you come up with a total bid of
$472,997.20.
Happy to answer any questions. I do
recommend approval.
>> Any questions or comments from the
committee?
Any public comment in the room on this
item?
Public comment in the room.
We'll go to public comment online.
No public comment online. We'll close
public comment, come back to the
committee. What's your pleasure?
>> Mr. Chair, I move to accept the bid from
Floyd's Truck Center, Inc.,
from right here in Cheyenne, Wyoming, in
an amount not to exceed $472,997.90.
>> Second.
>> The move by Councilman Knight, second by
Councilman Moody. Any further questions
or comments?
All in favor signify by saying I.
So that
Seeing that that recommendation is
unanimous,
the recommendation from the Finance
Committee, the next governing body will
be to accept this bid.
Next item.
>> Number 38, consideration of bid number
S-17-26
for a contract between the City of
Cheyenne and JTL Group, Incorporated,
doing business as Knife River for the
2026 Safe Routes to School project.
>> Staff report.
>> Um good afternoon, Chairman Esquibel and
members of the Finance Committee. Tom
Cobb, City Engineer, once again in front
of you. And by the way, I am growing my
goatee back, so Mr. White won't be
confused anymore.
Before you Before you and for your
consideration is obviously the bid
between uh
shine and GTL group. This was bid
S-17-26.
We did only receive one bid.
We were a little disappointed in that
fact, but this work will include ADA
ramp modification school zone device
upgrades and payment marking upgrades to
both Alta Vista, Bags Elementary, Davis
Elementary and Rossman Elementary. The
bid was reviewed by Mr. Ammon and myself
and we recommend
approval of this for the lowest
responsible bidder to award the JP JTL
group doing business as Knife River. The
total contract amount was $671,369.
The funding for this will come between
two sources, a community development
block grant in the amount of 521369
and the format foundation grant in the
amount of 150,000. And with that I'll
take any questions you might have for
me.
>> Councilman White.
>> Mr. Chair through you.
Um
Mr. Cobb, Councilman Moody and myself
have been very interested in school
zones and and uh
uh
speeding through them and and safety
measures. So could you describe what
some of those school zone device
upgrades will be?
>> Chairman through you to Councilman
White. So a lot of what Rick has been
working on lately is then now in
conjunction with the school zone areas
they're installing radar feedback signs
within those areas so that we can
monitor those speeds as well as it gives
them a highlight of how fast they're
actually going. We found those to be
very effective through our critical
traffic program and so we're we're
starting to install those. We're also or
going to put
uh some new crosswalks at Rossman and
again with the ADA upgrades. So that
answers your question, sir.
>> Councilman Moody.
>> Yep. Thank you Mr. Chair through you.
Thank you Mr. Cobb. Um
I'll go off of my colleague from Ward 1
uh, the pavement marking upgrades. Could
you just let the public know what that
entails?
>> Chairman, through you to Councilman
Moody. Yes, sir. So, there'll be new new
crosswalks and and markings. They're
thermoplastic pavement markings,
permanent markings.
>> Thank you.
>> Councilman Wolf.
>> Um, and thank you, Mr. Chairman. Through
you, um, Director Cobb, um,
is is there any significance in your
judgment, um,
about why you only got one bidder for
this?
>> Chairman, through you to to Councilman
Wolf. The answer is everyone is just
very busy. Um, that's the answer. I
mean, it wasn't out of line from where
we thought it would be. It was within
the ballpark. Um, slightly higher, but
um, I not not worth noting.
>> And, Mr. Chairman, just a brief
follow-up. I like um, thank you. Um,
and this isn't particularly highly
specialized work. I I assume that that
this is work many It's just the
contractors are all swamped with other
projects.
>> Chairman, through you to Councilman
Wolf. Yes, they are. And then, we their
sub is is Casper Electric, so they're
actually coming down to do the
electrical work.
>> Okay, we'll go to public comment in the
room.
Any public comment in the room on this
item?
Seeing none, public comment online.
No public comment online. Okay, we'll
close public public comment, come back
to the committee.
What's your pleasure?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to accept the bid
in amount not to exceed $671,369.00.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Moody,
second by Councilman White. Any further
comments? Councilman Moody.
>> Uh, thank you, Mr. Chairman. Through
you,
I just want to say it's a good start,
but it's still not enough for the safety
of our, uh, school zones. And even
looking into the flock systems. I know
it's not in there, but I do think we
need to continue doing these
improvements because our constituents
demand it. I mean, I would like to see
one even for hopefully another flock
system at one of these uh
more uh school zones that could be
dangerous. Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
>> A flock system or hawk system?
Flock or hawk?
Hawk.
Okay.
All in favor signify by saying aye.
And you see that that vote is unanimous,
the recommendation the next meeting of
the governing body will be to accept the
bid seeing that there are no more items
in front of this committee. We are
adjourned.
And Councilman White will do the action
report for set the governing body.
I'll be uh
joining you on Zoom.
Maybe.